JOY C. TEMPKINS

4487 Post Place, #103 • Nashville, TN 37205 • 615.354.0018 • jtempkins@gmail.com

PRINT PRODUCTION

Twenty-five + years directing and coordinating internal and external cross functional teams. Experienced in rotogravure, lithography, flexography, digital print and print quality management. Lead teams of production artists, designers, prepress and print quality.

- Contributor: Of particular note in 2015, generated over \$1 million in savings for client through development of a change in print process and design.
- Partner: Serve as key team member successfully working with cross-functional groups to deliver critical strategies.
- **Problem-Solver**: Ability to develop and implement creative and innovative solutions to challenges.
- Business Strategist: Proven ability to leverage the core competencies of an organization to take advantage of
 opportunities and implement solutions.
- Leader: Reputation for leading high functioning global teams that provide significant value in streamlining process and delivering value to client

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SCHAWK INC., FRANKLIN, TN

2008 - Present

SENIOR PREPRESS PRODUCTION MANAGER

Schawk is a leading global brand production and deployment company providing services from premedia workflows to color and print quality management to photography, e-content and more. Schawk is the leading specialist in ensuring brand consistency, protecting brand equity and ensuring compliance with packaging regulations.

Leading print quality team to implement standards setting. Responsible for on-site packaging including project management for new designs, refresh designs and changes from concept through printer. Collaborate with stakeholders, working closely with each, to ensure successful print outcome. Troubleshoot print issues, introduce new processes and print methods, on-board printers and design agencies and educate clients. Develop prepress workflow, coordinate fingerprints, conduct press checks and print tests.

Implemented 7 color extended color gamut print process for client packaging that resulted in a minimum of 20% print cost saving. Converted print process to high definition plating affording shorter press make ready and higher quality print.

CRT CUSTOM PRODUCTS INC., NASHVILLE, TN

2001 - 2008

PREPRESS MANAGER

CRT Custom Products is a one-stop-shop for handling the manufacturing of cartons and CD packaging for the music and video industry.

Streamlined file intake and processing workflow improving throughput by 25%. Cross-trained prepress team improving file imposition, platemaking and die line development as well as creating a diverse and responsive staff.

Responsible for all prepress operations and systems from file submission to plating in a CTP environment. Manage staff, hardware and software. Implemented and managed quality control process.

LIGHTNING SOURCE INC., LAVERGNE, TN

2000 - 2001

DIRECTOR OF PRODUCTION OPERATIONS

Lightning Source, a division of Ingram Content Group, is a global print-on-demand and distribution provider to publishers of all sizes.

Responsibilities centered on the development and implementation of process and procedure for start-up premedia operations. I developed vendor relationships, researched and implemented alternative processing methods and had direct supervision of all eBook and POD premedia staff. I revamped the POD premedia operation to triple the throughput of titles from 150 to 450 titles per week while reducing staffing requirements. I was actively involved in the development of POD/eBook customized systems and directly responsible for the creation of the eBook conversion/distribution premedia process.

Cell: 615.354.0018 • Email: jtempkins @gmail.com

JOURNAL COMMUNICATIONS, NASHVILLE, TN

1999-2000

PRODUCTION DIRECTOR

Journal Communications is an award-winning custom magazine publisher specializing in state tourism guides, state and regional economic development publications, chamber of commerce-sponsored community magazines and membership-based corporate magazines. Founded in 1988, JCI publishes more than 30 magazines ranging in circulation from 5.000 to 3.1 million.

Responsible for all custom publishing including travel related sport and client sponsored publications. I oversaw all aspects from concept, data collection, production and print processes to budget development and quoting. I streamlined the automated process from data collection to magazine page pagination.

ATHLON SPORTS COMMUNICATIONS, NASHVILLE, TN

1996 - 1999

DIRECTOR OF PRODUCTION OPERATIONS

Athlon Sports Communications is a publisher for 15 preseason sports annuals in professional baseball, golf, basketball, football and NASCAR along with College Football. In addition, they provide business-to-business communication programs, mailing and fulfillment services and wholesale and retail sports memorabilia sales.

Responsible for staffing, editorial concept and direction, design, photography, production and printing of magazines, newsletters, handbooks, contest and support materials. Administrative duties included the development and maintenance of 22 budgets, purchasing paper, printing and allied services, liaison between client service, sales, accounting, mailing and fulfillment, circulation and production. In addition, I was responsible for new product development and quoting special client projects. During my tenure with Athlon I reduced paper cost and consumption, brought the magazines in on-time and under budget and reduced total freelance staff required to produce each seasonal publication.

BASEBALL AMERICA INC., DURHAM, NC

1992 - 1996

GENERAL MANAGER

Baseball America is a national bi-weekly sports publication.

Responsible for increasing profitability through overhaul of all departments, personnel and time management while maintaining direct responsibility for subscription/newsstand circulation, book project development, production, planning and marketing with direct involvement in growth planning. Interfaced with company owned minor league baseball and hockey teams.

EDUCATION -

C.W. Post College The Effective Facilitator